Finding Aid for Shaké Ketefian papers, 1974-2011
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Shaké Ketefian papers 1974-2011, 1984-1999
Ketefian, Shaké.
4.5 linear feet
2012041 Aa 2
Professor at the University of Michigan School of Nursing and a leading scholar and researcher in nursing education, practice, and programs with an emphasis on international education. Collection consists of records of Ketefian's work with the School of Nursing as well as with the University Senate, and the Horace H. Rackham School of Graduate Studies.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Papers were received beginning in July 2010 (Donor no. 10704 ).
Periodic additions to the records expected.
Shake Ketefian papers are restricted under the University Executive Officers, Deans and Directors Records policy.
The collection includes records in the following categories
Executive Officer Records -- Boxes 1-4
Shaké Ketefian earned her B.S. in Nursing in 1963 from the American University of Beirut in Lebanon. At Columbia University she received a Master of Education with a specialization in Curriculum and Instruction in the area of Medical-Surgical Nursing in 1968, as well as an Ed.D. in Nursing Education in 1972.
Ketefian led a career as an instructor and researcher in the U.S. and abroad. Ketefian began teaching at the American University of Beirut in 1964 as an Assistant Instructor and later as Instructor of Nursing in 1968. In 1972 she became Assistant Professor of Nursing at New York University, a position that she held until 1976 when she was given the position of Associate Professor of Nursing. She was promoted to Chairperson of the Department of Advanced Education in Nursing Science, Division of Nursing NYU in 1981. She was made professor in 1982.
Her career in Michigan began in 1984 as Professor, Associate Dean for Graduate Studies and Director of the Doctoral Program at the School of Nursing. From 1991 to 1992 she was Acting Dean of the School of Nursing. She was appointed Director of Doctoral and Postdoctoral Studies at the School in 1992, Interim Associate Dean for Academic Affairs from 1993 to 1994, and Director of International Affairs from 1996 to 2010.
Ketefian was also actively involved in University-wide bodies and offices such as the University Senate and the Horace H. Rackham School of Graduate Studies. Within these, she served in the Rackham Executive Board from the late 1980s to the mid-1990s, as well as other Senate committees in the early 1990s.
She actively organized and chaired international conferences on doctoral nursing education as well as nursing professional associations and served on multiple editorial review boards for journals. Her research and publications focused on graduate nursing education, ethics and morals in nursing practice, research in nursing, nursing education globally and in the United States, assessment of nursing programs, environment for scholarship, and nursing science and practice in a global perspective.
Ketefian retired from active faculty status in May 31, 2010 and was named professor emeriti.
------------------------
Biographical Resources consulted:
School of Nursing Faculty and Staff page- http://nursing.umich.edu/faculty-staff/shak%C3%A9-ketefian (accessed 2011).
News and Information Services (University of Michigan) Faculty and Staff Files, Ketefian, Shaké file
Shaké Ketefian papers, Publications series, Curriculum Vitae
The Shaké Ketefian papers (4.5 linear feet) span from 1974 to 2011, and include correspondence, memoranda, publications, reports, presentations, and documentation related to her work in the School of Nursing as well as with the University Senate's Academic Affairs Advisory Committee, Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs, and the Horace H. Rackham School of Graduate Studies. The collection is comprised of five series: School of Nursing Administrative Files, School of Nursing Section, University Other, Rackham, and Publications. Each of the series is arranged in alphabetical order except for the Publications which are ordered by year.
Subjects:
Ketefian, Shaké.; Nursing--International cooperation.; Nursing--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Nursing--Study and teaching (Graduate); University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. School of Nursing.
- School of Nursing -- Administrative Files
  The School of Nursing Administrative Files (1980-2005) series contains records on the School's administration, deanship, committees, and councils. Among the subseries included are the Administrative Council, Curriculum Committee, the Dean's Council and the Appointments, Promotion and Tenure Committee.
  - Academic and Student Affairs Committee 2000-2001 (Box 1)
    [ER RESTRICTED until July 1, 2031 ]
  - Administrative Council
    - 1996-1997 (Box 1)
    - 1997-1998 (Box 1)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - Retreat and Task Force Spring-Summer 1985 (Box 1)
  - Admission, Progression and Grad Task Force (APGTF)
    - Admission, Progression and Grad Task Force 1984-1985 (Box 1)
    - Admission, Progression and Grad Task Force-GRE Validity Study 1980, 1984 (Box 1)
  - APT Appointments, Promotion and Tenure Committee
    - 1997-1998 (Box 1)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - Center for Nursing Research
    - 1996-1998 (Box 1)
  - Core Centers Grant Material 1994 (Box 1)
  - Continuing Education Task Force Report 1983 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence NLN Self-Study
    - Visitor's Report/ Addenda to Board of Review (Box 1)
  - Curriculum Committee
    - 1994-1995 (Box 1)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - Deans
    - Dean Hinshaw 1995-1996 (Box 1)
    - Deans 1995-1996 (Box 1)
    - Deans 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Dean's Council
    - 1988-1989 (Box 1)
    - 1989-1991 (Box 1)
  - Divisions
    - 1996-1997 (Box 1)
    - 1997-1998 (Box 1)
    - Divisions Director's Retreat 1999 (Box 2)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - Faculty Correspondence 1994-1997 (Box 2)
  - Faculty Minutes 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - Faculty Retreat May 1999 (Box 2)
  - FTE Workload Analysis, May / Fall 1988 (Box 2)
  - Graduate Faculty
    - 1994-1996 (Box 2)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - Graduate Studies Office Annual Report 1984 (Box 2)
  - N699 Task Force 2004-2005 (Box 2)
  - Office of Graduate Studies /Nursing Administration Program 1990-1991 (Box 2)
  - Program Assessment Undergraduate
    - Program Assessment Undergraduate (Box 2)
    - Master's Students Self-Assessment (Box 2)
    - Curriculum Committee 1986, 1993-1994 (Box 2)
  - Program Chairs 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Proposals and Relevant Articles-BS/MS, Single MS 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Task Force on Work Environment 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Technology Task Force
    - Proposals to Info Tech Division, Fall 1986 (Box 2)
    - Technology Task Force (Box 2)
  - UM Educational Computing Ad Hoc Committee 1986-1987 (Box 2)
- School of Nursing-Section
  The records in the School of Nursing Section (1984-2007) series are related to Ketefian's work with the School of Nursing like the previous series. However, in their original order, these were labeled differently from the rest of the collection with an "SN" identifier of the folders. We have decided to respect original order and tried to reflect the creator's distinction of these files with this series.
  - Accreditation UM/ Internationalization 2007
    - Annual Report / Accreditation 1996-1997 (Box 2)
  - Archival Report 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - Doctor of Nursing Practice Task Force 2004-2005 (Box 2)
  - Faculty / Faculty Service Role 2005-2006 (Box 2)
  - Historical Background (Box 2)
  - Information Technology Committee Articles 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - ITAC-IT Competencies 2002-2003 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous 2006-2007 (Box 3)
  - MUCIA Global-Discussions 1998-1999 (Box 3)
  - Ph.D. Program Review, AC/EC Fall 1998 (Box 3)
  - Plan (Evaluation Plan) 1989 (Box 3)
  - Planning (Long-Range) 1988 (Box 3)
  - Policies (Box 3)
  - Publications of Early graduates of PhD Program and Faculty
    - Recruitment/ Marketing Trester/ Marshall 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Task Force on International Nursing, Winter 1988 (Box 3)
- University Other
  The University Other (1986-1998) series comprises Ketefian's records from her work with University bodies outside of the School of Nursing such as the Academic Affairs Advisory Committee, the Senate Advisory Committee on Academic Affairs, the Vice-President for Academic and Multicultural Affairs among others.
  - Academic Affairs Advisory Committee (AAAC) 1997-1998
    - AAAC / Dean Evaluation 1998 (Box 3)
    - AAAC / SACUA (Senate Advisory Committee on Academic Affairs) 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Academic Affairs Advisory Committee (AAAC) 1998-1999 (Box 3)
  - By Law 14.06 TF 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - CESF Committee on the Economic Status of the Faculty Report 1991-1992 (Box 3)
  - Convocation/ Graduation 1991-1992 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence-University of Michigan
    - 1992-1993 (Box 3)
    - 1993-1994 (Box 3)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - Integrity of Scholarship Faculty Forum, Jan 1986 (Box 3)
  - Office of the Vice President for Research 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - Provost's Office
    - 1993-1994 (Box 3)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - Senate Assembly
    - SACUA Retreat on Cost-containment March 1991 (Box 3)
  - Senate Committee on Research and Scholarship
    - Senate Committee on Research and Scholarship, Spring 1986 (Box 3)
  - Vice President for Academic and Multicultural Affairs 1992-1993 > (Box 3)
- Rackham
  The Rackham (1984-1995) series contains records produced from Ketefian's collaboration with the Horace H. Rackham School of Graduate Studies. It includes materials from the Rackham Executive Board, correspondence, and additional documentation.
  - Rackham Correspondence (Box 4)
    - 1985-1987 (Box 4)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 4)
    - 1990-1992 (Box 4)
    - 1992-1993 (Box 4)
    - 1993-1994 (Box 4)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - Rackham Executive Board 1988-1989, 2 folders
    - 1989-1990 (Box 4)
    - 1990-1991, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Rackham Fellowships 1993-1994 (Box 4)
  - Rackham Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Report on Quality of School of Nursing Graduate Programs-Paper sent to Rackham November 1987 (Box 4)
  - Rackham Reviews of the School of Nursing Graduate Programs 1984 (Box 4)
  - AAU documents (Association of American Universities) (Box 4)
- Publications 1974-2011
  The Publications (1974-2011) series is arranged by year and contains Shaké Ketefian's published work, including presentations for conferences, from 1974 to 2011. Her curriculum vitae included in this section provides a reference list to her publications.
  - Curriculum Vitae (with list of publications) (Box 5)
  - 1974-1989 (Box 5)
  - 1990-1994 (Box 5)
  - 1996-1999 (Box 5)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 5)
  - 2002, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - 2003 (Box 5)
  - 2004 (Box 5)
  - 2005 (Box 5)
  - 2006-2007 (Box 5)
  - 2008-2009 (Box 5)
  - 2010-2011 (Box 5)
  - Date unknown (Box 5)